General Manuscripts Miscellaneous Collection, 1502-2012: Finding Aid C0140
Manuscripts Division
General Manuscripts Miscellaneous Collection
1502-2012
Manuscripts Division
Princeton University. Library. Special Collections
C0140
108 boxes
61.8 linear feet
Consists of over 3000 miscellaneous items of primarily American literary, historical, and political figures, including business and personal letters, manuscripts, drawings, photographs, and official documents.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of over 3000 miscellaneous items of primarily American literary, historical, and political figures, including business and personal letters, cards, manuscripts, drawings, photographs, and official documents (deeds, wills, bonds, etc.). This miscellaneous collection provides a way of locating small accessions of material that are not part of the Manuscripts Division's provenance-based or topical collections.
The collection includes documents from United States presidents James Buchanan, Millard Fillmore, Ulysses S. Grant, Warren G. Harding, Rutherford B. Hayes, Herbert Hoover, Richard Nixon, Ronald Reagan, William Howard Taft, and Martin Van Buren. The collection also contains original documents of Alexander Graham Bell, Andrew Carnegie, Winston Churchill, Charles Darwin, Jefferson Davis, Frederick Douglass, Sigmund Freud, Langston Hughes, Victor Hugo, Herman Melville, J. P. Morgan, Samuel Morse, Benito Mussolini, Friedrich Nietzsche, George Orwell, Thomas Paine, Edgar Allan Poe, Paul Revere, J. D. Salinger, Jean-Paul Satre, William Tecumseh Sherman, Upton Sinclair, Henry Morton Stanley, John Steinbeck, Bram Stoker, Alexis de Toqueville, Jules Verne, Booker T. Washington, E. B. White, and Virginia Woolf, to name only a few of the most famous.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by the name of the creator, with unattributed materials at the end.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection has resulted from miscellaneous purchases and gifts of numerous donors over the years.
Appraisal
No material was separated during processing.
Accruals
The collection is open and will continue to grow.
Existence and Location of Copies
Parts of this collection are available on microfilm, cataloged separately as RCPXM-7497696.
Authors.; Poets.; Politicians -- United States.; Presidents -- United States.; Documents.; Letters.; Manuscripts.; Photographs.
- Abbey, Edwin Austin, Mrs., 1852-1911, 1930; 1 box (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  ALS to Ms. Meta Harren, 27 August 1930, 2 pp. AM 21233
- Abbey, Henry E. (Henry Eugene), 1882; 1 box (Box 1)
  DS regarding fire insurance payment, 3 November 1882.
- Abbot, William Richardson, 1825; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to his father, John Abbot, 13 November 1825.
- Abel, Othemio, 1875-1976, 1927; 1 box (Box 1)
  TLS (in German) to Professor W. B. Scott (Princeton University Department of Geology), 10 May 1927. AM 12513
- Abercromby, Lady, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Dr. Humpgrey, 14 June. AM 12984
- Aberdeen, George Hamilton-Gordon, 4th Earl of, 1784-1860, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Sir Thomas Lawrence, 5 May (?), 1 receipt to Lord Viscount Casthereagh (?), 2 portraits (printed by London Printing and Publishing Company). AM 17867, 18565
- About, Edmund, 1828-1885, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS (to ?).
- Account of the hacienda of San José de Acolman and other properties confiscated from the Jesuits in Mexico, 1767; Librería de Antaño; 1 folder (Box 1)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Librería de Antaño in 2021 (AM 2022-033).
  A manuscript account of the hacienda of San José de Acolman and other properties in Mexico which were confiscated from the Jesuits, as part of the 1767 general expulsion by Charles III. The title page reads, "Testimonio del quaderno quinto de las diligencias... con arreglamiento a las superiores ordenes sobre la confiscación de las temporalidades de los Religiosos de la Sagrada Compañıá de Jesús en las haciendas de San Joseph de Acolman."
  Jesuits -- History -- 18th century; Haciendas -- Mexico
- Adam, Adolphe, 1803-1856, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS with envelope (to ?).
- Adam, Juliette, 1836-1936, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ANs (in French) to "Mon cher ami."
- Adam, M. T., Rev, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  3 ALsS to Henry F. Lee (seminary student in Princeton, N. J.), 19 March 1852 - 30 October 1852. AM 12608
- Adam, Robert Borthwick, 1863-1940, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  TLS to A. Edward Newton, 2 pp., 2 February 1920. AM 22077
- Adams, Alice, 1926; 1 box (Box 1)
  "Statement of Isabel Hastings Shiver and.. .," 5 pp., 4 November 1926. AM 9295
- Adams, Charles Francis, 1807-1886, circa 1869; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Professor J. R. Linell in Boston, Mass., 23 December 1869 (?). AM 13834
- Adams, Darwin James, 1938; 1 box (Box 1)
  TLsS to W. R. Compton Jr., 12 October 1938, New York, n.d. AM 13977
- Adams, Henry Brooks, 1838-1918, 1876; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to F. B. Sanborn, 5 March 1876. AM 20842
- Adams, James Trustlow, 1879-1949, 1942; 1 box (Box 1)
  TLS to Thomas Brumbaugh, complying with his request for Adam's autograph, 17 August 1942. AM 87-24
- Ade, George, 1866-1944, 1908; 1 box (Box 1)
  2 TLD to Robert Mountsier, 30 June 1908 - 24 August 1908. AM 15296
- Adee, Alvey A. (Alvey Augustus), 1842-1924, 1894; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to General Canevaro, 1894. AM 14009
- Adenauer, Konrad, 1876-1967, 1966; 1 box (Box 1)
  TLS (in German) to Frau Dulles, 10 January 1966. AM 18852
- Agassiz Alexander Emanuel Rudolph, 1875; 1 box (Box 1)
  3 ALsS to William H. Flower, 21 April 1875, Cambridge, Mass. AM 11339
- Agassiz, Louis, i.e. Jean Louis Rodolphe, 1807-1873, 1871; 1 box (Box 1)
  2 ALsS to Madame and William H. Flower, 20 January 1871 - 21 October 1871. AM 11340
- Agnew, Cornelius Rea, 1830-1888, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  2 ALsS to "Dear Sir," 16 January 1880. AM 21292, 21293
- Aiken, Conrad Potter, 1889-1973, 1972; 1 box (Box 1)
  TCsS by Jay Dillon, January 1972.
- Aiken, James R, 1863; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to "Uncle Daniel Joquish (?)," 13 January 1863. AM 2004-133
- Ainger, Alfred, 1837-1904, 1887; 1 box (Box 1)
  2 ALsS to James Dykes Campbell, 15-22 November 1887. AM 20844
- Alford, John, 1753; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Jonathan Sargent, Charlestown, Mass., 5 March 1753. AM 265
- Alford, Margaret, 1762; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Jonathan Sargent, Charlestown, Mass., 24 July 1762. AM 266
- Albee, John, 1911; 1 box (Box 1)
  3 ALsS to Charles W. Jenke, Washington DC, 7 December 1911. AM 12807
- Alcott, E. H, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Mr. Shubert, Brookline, Mass..
- Alcott, Amos Bronson, 1799-1888, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  Photogrpah, "Carte de visite," in Boston, Mass.
- Alcott, William A, 1833; 1 box (Box 1)
  2 ALsS to Mr. Merriam, 22 October 1833 - 17 April 1833.
- Alden, J. C., Pages from American Revolutionary War Orderly Books, 1775 December 15-1776 January 12; 1 folder (Box B-001555, Folder 7)
  Purchased from William Reese Company in 2021 (AM 2021-52).
  Consists of fourteen handwritten pages taken from one or possibly more orderly books kept by aides-de-camp to Generals Artemus Ward and George Washington during the early stages of the American Revolutionary War and the Siege of Boston. The orders contained on these leaves, written during the siege, record a variety of official internal actions taken by the nascent Continental Army and include regimental orders, general orders, notifications of troop movements, records of guard duty, as well as matters relating to discipline, training, supplies, and food. Most notably, they refer to the potential participation of free African American volunteers in military roles. Names mentioned in the orderly book pages include Colonel Read, Colonel Danielson, Major Mitchel, Colonel Alden, Lieutenant Goodwin, Jedediah Huntington, Captain Ingersoll, Major Barnes, General Horatio Gates, and numerous others, some of whom are listed as participants in courts martial proceedings. Regarding authorship, the final page is signed by J. C. (or possibly I. C.) Alden, which could refer to either Ichabod Alden or a fellow member of the Massachusetts Alden family, such as a John or Joseph C. Alden. It is also possible that another person authored some of the leaves since there are at least two different handwriting styles.
  United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Participation, African American -- Sources; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Sources; Boston (Mass.) -- History -- Siege, 1775-1776; Orderly books -- 18th century; United States. Continental Army; Washington, George, 1732-1799.; Ward, Artemas, 1727-1800
- Aldington, Richard, 1892-1962, 1 box (Box 1)
  3 TLsS to Rochelle Girson, 17 February 1962 - 28 March 1962.
- Alembert, Jean Lerond d', 1717-1783, 1750-1752; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS (to "Monsieur"), 1750-1752. AM 16148
- Alexander, Caroline, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  Ams, "Her Romance," 52 pp.
- Alexander, Isaac, 1773; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Andrew Hunter, Mecklinburg County, N. C., 29 April 1773. AM 9159
- Alexander, Joseph, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  Photostat of will, 1760. AM 16166.
- Alfonso, XIII, King of Spain, 1886-1941, 1918; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to the President of Costa Rica, 3 June 1918. AM 20539
- Alford, Margaret, 1762; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Jonathan Sargeant, Charlestown, Mass., 24 July 1762. AM 266
- Ali-Cohen, E. S, 1921; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to John Burns, 16 March 1921. AM 12795
- Alison, Dorothea, 1781; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS (photostat) to her sister, Charlestown, Mass., 14 May 1781. AM 9356
- Allen, Elizabeth Ann Akers, 1832-1911, 1874; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Mary L. Booth, New York, n.d., 5 March 1874. AM 80-79
- Allen, E. T, 1876; 1 box (Box 1)
  3 ALsS to "Gents," San Francisco, 24 January 1876 - 7 June 1876.
- Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897, 1875; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to William H. Flower, Philadelpia, PA., 31 December 1875.
- Allen, Henry T. (Henry Tureman), 1859-1930, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  TLS to Brackenride Long, Washington, DC., 18 December 1923.
- Allen, Hervey, 1889-1949, 1941; 1 box (Box 1)
  TLS to Captain F. L. Pleadwell, Florida, 8 April 1941. AM 20845
- Allen, James L, 1846; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to his wife, Caroline, account of his trip from Cincinati to Washington, describing transportation and fellow passengers, reporting news of fighting in Texas and that Congress is about to declare war, 19 May 1846. AM 13317
- Allen, Job, M, 1837; 1 box (Box 1)
  AMss (photostats) of his journal, 1837. AM 10953
- Allen, Joel Asaph, 1838-1921, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to William H. Flower, Cambridge, Mass., 1 February 1881. AM 11343
- Allenby, Edmund Henry Hyndman, Viscount, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  AN from Viscountess Allenby, n.d. AM 16047
- Allentuck, Marcia, 1928, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  5 Acs, 3 TLsS from E. D. H. Johnson, Walt Litz, J. R. Martin, and Henry Miller, 24 March 1971 - 12 April 1974. AM 2008-104
- Allier, Achille, Letter to William Tudor, 1829; 1 folder (Box 1)
  "Autograph letter signed by a Papal diplomat in Peru to American diplomat William Tudor in Brazil, written days after the Battle of Tarqui and concerning the liberator Simón Bolívar and the wars and unrest in South and Central America. Allier describes the 'sad situation' in Peru in his letter - written entirely in French - and comments on the wars and unrest in South and Central America. He discusses the political fortunes of the great Liberator and leader of Gran Colombia, Simón Bolívar, who helped establish rpublican government there and gain independence from Spanish colonizers." - Description from dealer.
  Purchased from Ian Brabner, Bookseller in March 2021 (AM 2021-072).
  Tarqui, Battle of, Ecuador, 1829; Gran Colombia-Peru War, 1828-1829; Tudor, William, 1779-1830; Bolívar, Simón, 1783-1830
- Alliluyeva, Svetlene Stalina, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS to Mr. William Dix, 7 June 1970. AM 20454
- Alma- Tadema, Lawrence, Sir, 1836-1912, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  ALS ro "My dear Waterlow," 2 May 1912. AM 20442
- Alma- Tadema, Lawrence, Sir, 1836-1912, 1890-1906; 1 box (Box 1)
  10 ALsS to "Mrs. Coronio," 1890-1906. AM 2002-88
- Almon. John, 1737-1805, undated; 1 box (Box 1)
  Manuscript notes and miscellaneous material, mainly about his friend John Wilkes. AM 2010-46
- Altschul, Frank, 1887-1981, 1923; 1 box (Box 1)
  TLS to Elmer Adler.
- The American Philosophical Society, 1786; 1 box (Box 2)
  DS to George Morgan, 20 January 1786, TLs to the president of Princeton University. AM 8838, 14306
- American Revolution Bicentennial Administration, Pinbacks and Comic Book Pages Celebrating Deborah Sampson Gannett and Crispus Attucks, 1976; American Revolution Bicentennial Administration; 1 folder (Box B-001559, Folder 15)
  Purchased from Cowan's Auctions in 2021 (AM 2021-68).
  Consists of materials celebrating Crispus Attucks (1723-1770) and Deborah Sampson Gannett (1760-1827) as African American Revolutionary War heroes. Two pin-back buttons from the American Revolution Bicentennial Administration describe Attucks and Sampson as Black American Patriots, noting Attucks as the first man to die for "American freedom" and Gannett as the first woman to fight in the Continental Army. There are also two comic book pages with illustrations and descriptions of Attucks and Gannett. One of the comic book pages is signed "E. Jackson," and both appear to be designed by the same artist.
  African Americans -- History -- To 1863 -- Sources; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Participation, African American -- Sources; Buttons (information artifacts) -- 20th century; Comic books -- 20th century; Gannett, Deborah Sampson, 1760-1827; Attucks, Crispus, -1770
- Anonymous, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  "Tha-Copay-O-Jeb-Be-Way," Ojibway Indian Play, AMs, n.d. AM 19827
- Anthony, Susan Brownell, 1820-1906, 1882; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to "My Dear Elizabeth," 19 January 1882. AM 16283
- Apache School of Indian Basket Weaving, 1903; 1 box (Box 2)
  TL to "Dear Madam," enclosing circulars and samples (present), 16 November 1903. WA 1994-13
- Appleton, Nathaniel, 1693-1784, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to the "Commissioners for Indian Affairs," n.d. AM 13010
- Appleton, Samuel, 1766-1853, 1836; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS from Boston, Mass., 5 May 1836. AM 20905
- Apgar, Ellis, A, 1884; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to the editor of the Herald, 24 March 1884. AM 2006-91
- Archer, Willaim, 1896-1906; 1 box (Box 2)
  7 ALsS to Edgar Jepson, 3 November 1896 - 14 May 1906, 2 ALsS to Luther E. Price, 29 April 1097 - 5 April 1908. AM 11334,11656, 11657, 11658, 11661, 11662
- Apollinaire, Guillaume, 1880-1918, 1901; 1 box (Box 2)
  12 ALsS (copies) to Linda Molina da Sllva. AM 77-116
- Anway, Ross C, 1908; 1 box (Box 2)
  Journal (xerox) of seamen on USS Wisconsin, 50 pp., 7 July 1908 - 22 February 1909. AM 89-4
- Andrews, Mathew, 1934; 1 box (Box 2)
  TLS to J. L. Davis, 5 January 1934. AM 18549
- The American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society, 1945; 1 box (Box 2)
  TL (mimeograph) to Governor Walter E. Edge, 10 April 1945. AM 13791
- Ames, Mary Clemmer, 1839-1884, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Miss Booth, 3 October 1873. AM 80-79
- Anderson, Charles Roberts, 1902-1999, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  "Melville's English Debut," (reprinted from American Literature). AM 48404
- Anderson, Jacob, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ADS for Benjamin Guild, 24 August 1804-20 February 1807. AM 1578-1582
- Andre, John, 1751-1780, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  2 ALsS to M. Caleb Cope Lancaster; "Particulars of the Mischianza" (from the Ladies Magazine), 1792; 2 TMs (bioagraphies of John Andre); 3 pictures drawn by Andre. AM 158229
- Angell, Norman, Sir, 1874-1967, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALD to "Dearest B," 15 January 1964.
- Ammidown's Historical Collection, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  "Confederate money."
- Anonymous, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  "A Caual Client of a Country Lawyer," Ams, 2 pp. AM 13534
- Archer, Stevenson, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Secretary I. K. Paulding of the Navy. AM 1 Pyne Henry
- Arden, Elizabeth, 1878-1966, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Madame Cheruy, n.d. AM 18608
- Argyll, George Douglas Campbell, Duke of, 1823-1900, 1855-1879; 1 box (Box 2)
  17 ALsS to Dr. James McCosh concerning a variety of matters, 1855-1879. AM 11587 - 11604
- Arizona (Ariz.), undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS (by unknown) to his niece "Annie," 19 March 1883. AM 2004-162
- Armellini, Mariano, 1852-1896, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  "Sonetto del Signor Armellini," poem, n.d. AM 19586
- Armistead, George, 1780-1818, 1803; 1 box (Box 2)
  Photostat of ADS, certification of receipt of annuities by Six Nations of Indians, 30 October 1803. AM 17484
- Armour, Alexander William, 1947; 1 box (Box 2)
  2 TLsS from Kenneth S.Gapp, 13 December 1947. AM 14239
- Armour, Geroge Allison, Class of 1877, 1916; 1 box (Box 57)
  12 by 16 in. DS from Classics Department of Princeton, recognizing 60 years of service, in Latin with translation, 1916. AM 17059
- Armour, Richard, 1906-1989, 1984-1985; 1 box (Box 2)
  3 TLsS to Harold W. McGraw, 2 TLs from Harold W. McGraw, 21 December 1984 - 17 August 1985. AM 1994-5
- Armstrong, John, 1758-1843, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to M. Bourne, 1809; ALS (photostat) to Lady Albany, 1835; ALS to Captain McConnel, 17 May 1788, Receipt, 27 June 1767. AM 271, 17484, 9140
- Armstrong, John, 1758-1843, 1803-1805; 1 box (Box 2)
  8 ALsS to Thomas Tillotson of Albany, N.Y., 1803-1805. AM 86-122
- Armstrong, John, 1758-1843, 1845; 1 box (Box 2)
  autograph, Paris, 25 April 1845. AM 10858
- Armstrong, Richard, 1825; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Andrew Guffy in Princeton, N.J., 7 November 1825. AM 86-102
- Arnold, Frances, 1880; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Edward L. Pierce, 1 September 1880. AM 9652
- Arrowsmith, William, 1924-1992, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  3 poems by Arrowsmith, TLS to Mr. Boyd, n.d.. AM 12584
- Arrowsmith, William, 1924-1992, 1964-1974; 1 box (Box 2)
  TLsS from authors (Ronald Bottrall, David Garnett, Mary Renault.. .), 1964-1974. AM 1994-18
- Arthur, Chester Alan, 1829-1886, 1862-1882; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to General Jos B. Carr, 1881; ALS to John Rider, 1862; Signed Check, 1881; ALS to "The President," 1882. AM 13834, 1997-51
- Ashley, Leonard R. N, 1952; 1 box (Box 2)
  Notes (autograph) from poetry reading, 1952. AM 2001-06
- Asquith, H. H. (Herbert Henry), 1852-1928, 1917; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Mr. Browne, 10 April 1917. AM 17925
- Asquith, Lady Cynthia, 1887-1960, 1933; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Jon Gawsworth, 24 June 1933. AM 22047
- Astor, William Waldorf, Viscount, 1848-1919, 1922; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Cyrus H. McCormick, 27 May 1922. AM 13365
- Atherton, Gertrude Franklin Horn, 1857-1948, 1917; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS (to ?), 1 February 1917. AM 13257
- Auberm D. F E. (Daniel Francois Esprit), 1782 - 1871, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ANS (in French), n. d..
- d'Aubigne, Merle, 1872; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS (in French) to "Cher Colligue," 28 May 1872. AM 9772
- Auchincloss, Louis, 1990-1992; 1 box (Box 2)
  Correspondence with Gloria Erlich regarding her book The Sexual Education of Edith Wharton. AM 2011-103
- Austen, E. F, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to "Mr. Chapman," 3 February (?). AM 19030
- Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Dr. Browne, 1909; 7 ALsS to Smith, Elder & Co., 1862- 1879. AM 16116, 15157
- Austin, Sarah, 1793-1867, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Mr. Buckley, n.d. AM 19607
- Austin, William Henry, Letter to Ada Caroline Austin Martin, 1864 February 22; Austin, William Henry, 1840-1914; 1 folder (Box B-001683, Folder 6)
  Purchased from Swann Auction Galleries in 2021 (AM 2022-056).
  Consists of a four-page letter from William Henry Austin (1840-1914), a sergeant in the 109th New York Infantry during the American Civil War, to his sister, Ada Caroline Austin Martin (1834-1923) of Harpursville, Broome County, New York. Austin writes from Camp Briggs in Alexandria, Virginia, and describes an encounter with Lyons (Sarah Rosetta) Wakeman (1843-1864), a gender non-conforming person who is known as one of the few women to serve in the Union Army. However, Wakeman was enlisted in the 153rd New York Infantry and later buried under the name of Lyons Wakeman and often presented as a man. Austin and Wakeman were childhood friends whose families resided in neighboring villages, and thus Austin was one of the few soldiers who knew of Wakeman's enlistment story. Of his encounter with Wakeman, Austin writes, "She was looking fine. Sports an insipid moustache, highly colored, presents quite a soldier's appearance. There is something mighty queer about this arrangement. There is rottenness in Denmark somewhere (mum about this)." He also writes about other soldiers, his pay, and potential romantic interests back home.
  Gender-nonconforming people -- United States -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Soldiers -- New York (State) -- History -- 19th century -- Correspondence; Alexandria (Va.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Women -- Sources; Correspondence -- 19th century; Wakeman, Sarah Rosetta, 1843-1864
- Autographs, undated; 1 box (Box 2)
  Miscellaneous signatures. AM 17728, 1996-29
- Axson, Stockton, 1867-1935, 1914; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Hubertis Cummings, 12 June 1940; 6 ALsS (photostats) to John Grier Hibben, 20 November 1913 - 28 July 1924. AM 18222, 12871
- Axson, Stockton (contd.), 1867-1935, 1916-1925; 1 box (Box 2)
  12 TLs from Lawrence C. Woods, 5 TLsS, 2 ALS to Lawrence C. Woods, 9 September 1916 - 2 June 1925. AM 18221
- Axson, Stockton (contd.), 1867-1935, 1899; 1 box (Box 2)
  ALS to Edward Dowden, 23 September 1899. AM 10950
- B., Tom, 1920; 1 box (Box 3)
  ALS to "My Dear Randal" 10 April 1920. AM 9801
- Babbitt, Milton, 1916, 1993; 1 box (Box 3)
  ALS to Don. C. Skemer, 10 September 1993. AM 1994-34
- Babcock, Edwina Stanton, undated; 1 box (Box 3)
  TLS to Parke E. Doland, n.d. AM 13475
- Babler, Otto F, 1931; 1 box (Box 3)
  ACS to "Mr. Whilly" regarding his own translation of Poe's the "Raven" into Czech, 24 November 1931. AM 13328
- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750, undated; 1 box (Box 3)
  Fragment of Bach's Cantata 168 (2nd violin part), n.d. AM 18807
  Annotations in Italian and German.
- Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1801-1881, 1811-1870; 1 box (Box 3)
  4 ALsS to his mother, 1811-1814; 2 ALsS with his father, 1814; "Memorandum of Sunday Clothing," 1811,"Evaluation of the Estate of Mr. Bache," n.d., D for Cathering Bache, 1814; AN from Jos. Alden, 1870. AM 14666
- Bache, Catherine, 1815-1817; 1 box (Box 3)
  Memorandum regarding Catherine's tract in the plains of Penn's Landing, 1815-1817. AM 8977
- Bacheler, H. M., M. D, 1879- 1883; 1 box (Box 3)
  ALS to George W. Lyon regarding accout of David Livingston's gun and bell, 9 October 1886.
- Bacon, Alice Mabel, 1858-1918, 1910; 1 box (Box 3)
  ALS to Mrs. Tyson, 23 October 1910. AM 16414
- Bacon, John, 1777-1859, undated; 1 box (Box 3)
  ALS to Dr. Johnson, 5 May 1829.
- Bacon, Leonard, 1887-1954, undated; 1 box (Box 3)
  "The Critic Thinks.. .," poem, n.d. AM 16064
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919, 1908; 1 box (Box 3)
  TLS to "Sir," 1908. AM 14009
- Baden, Powell, 1935; 1 box (Box 3)
  TLS to Luther Edmunds Price, 26 July 1935. AM 11028
- Bagot, Lewis, 1741-1802, undated; 1 box (Box 3)
  4 ALsS to Rev. Walter Bagot, ALS to Walter from Mary Bagot, 2 packets of hair belonging to Walter and William Bagot. AM 19719
- Bailey, Alexander Hamilton, 1817-1874, 1867-1868; 1 box (Box 3)
  ALS to Ben Perley Poore, 4 December 1867; TL from Ben Perley Poore concerning the "Congressional Directory," 5 December 1868. AM 36 Pyne Henry
- Bailey, Dix & Mead, Cabinet Card Photograph of Sitting Bull, 1882; Bailey, Dix & Mead; 1 folder (Box B-001584, Folder 12)
  Purchased from Cowan's Auctions in 2021 (AM 2022-021).